[
    {
        "question": "39. In ideal conditions a truck or bus with an air brake going at 55 mph would require stopping distance of how many feet?",
        "choices": [
            "From 100 to 250 feet.",
            "Less than 100 feet.",
            "More than 300 feet."
        ],
        "answer": "More than 300 feet."
    },
    {
        "question": "40. It is not safe to drive a vehicle that has brake drums with cracks that are longer than of the width of the friction area.",
        "choices": [
            "1/2",
            "1/4",
            "1/32"
        ],
        "answer": "1/2"
    },
    {
        "question": "41. Why must air tanks be drained?",
        "choices": [
            "To drain all the air out of the tank.",
            "To drain moisture and oil out of tank.",
            "To tell you how much air is in the air tanks."
        ],
        "answer": "To drain moisture and oil out of tank."
    },
    {
        "question": "42. It is possible to have an air leak in one system which will not affect the other.",
        "choices": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "43. Both systems run off of the same air compressor, so if one air compressor malfunctions you will not be able to build or maintain pressure in either system.",
        "choices": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "44. All vehicles with air brakes must have a low-pressure warning signal.",
        "choices": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "45. What are spring brakes?",
        "choices": [
            "Brakes used for parking.",
            "If the air brakes leak down, springs press the brakes on to stop the vehicle.",
            "The spring on the brake pedal."
        ],
        "answer": "If the air brakes leak down, springs press the brakes on to stop the vehicle."
    },
    {
        "question": "46. Front wheel brakes are good under all conditions.",
        "choices": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "47. When you apply your brakes, the air brake system works with an electric switch, by air pressure, to turn on the brake lights.",
        "choices": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "48. What do air brakes use to make the brakes work?",
        "choices": [
            "Compressed gas.",
            "Compressed oil.",
            "Compressed air."
        ],
        "answer": "Compressed air."
    },
    {
        "question": "49. The service brake applies and releases:",
        "choices": [
            "The parking brake when you use the parking brake control.",
            "The brake when you use the brake pedal during normal driving.",
            "In the event of an emergency."
        ],
        "answer": "The brake when you use the brake pedal during normal driving."
    },
    {
        "question": "50. The parking brake applies and releases:",
        "choices": [
            "The brake pedal during normal driving.",
            "In the event of an emergency.",
            "The parking brakes when you use the parking brake control."
        ],
        "answer": "The parking brakes when you use the parking brake control."
    },
    {
        "question": "51. The emergency brake system:",
        "choices": [
            "Uses parts of the service and parking brake system to stop the vehicle in the event of a brake system failure.",
            "Uses the service brake to stop the vehicle in the event of a brake system failure.",
            "Uses the parking brake to stop the vehicle in the event of a brake system failure."
        ],
        "answer": "Uses parts of the service and parking brake system to stop the vehicle in the event of a brake system failure."
    },
    {
        "question": "52. The governor controls when the air compressor will pump into the air storage tanks.",
        "choices": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "53. When the air pressure falls to the minimum pressure allowed in the system, the governor prevents more air from escaping the air tanks.",
        "choices": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "54. The storage tanks are used to hold compressed air.",
        "choices": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "55. When you put the brakes on by pushing down on the brake pedal:",
        "choices": [
            "The air pressure is reduced to the brake pads.",
            "Air pressure is applied to the brake pads.",
            "Compressed air is let go out of the system."
        ],
        "answer": "Air pressure is applied to the brake pads."
    },
    {
        "question": "56. The S-cam forces the brake shoes away from one another and presses them against the inside of the brake drum. It is called the S-cam because:",
        "choices": [
            "It is shaped like the letter 'Z'",
            "It is shaped like the letter 'N'.",
            "It is shaped like the letter 'S'."
        ],
        "answer": "It is shaped like the letter 'S'."
    },
    {
        "question": "57. What is a dual air brake system?",
        "choices": [
            "A two brake system, one operates the front brakes and one operates the back brakes.",
            "A two braking system, one for each side of the vehicle.",
            "A two braking system, one for daytime and one for nighttime driving."
        ],
        "answer": "A two brake system, one operates the front brakes and one operates the back brakes."
    },
    {
        "question": "58. What are the slack adjusters?",
        "choices": [
            "It is the space between the back wheels.",
            "It is an adjusting nut on the backside of the brake drum used for adjusting the brakes.",
            "It is an adjusting nut under the cab to adjust the springs."
        ],
        "answer": "It is an adjusting nut on the backside of the brake drum used for adjusting the brakes."
    },
    {
        "question": "59. How can you check the slack adjuster?",
        "choices": [
            "Park on level ground, turn off parking brakes, pull hard on each slack adjuster. It shouldn't move more than one inch.",
            "Park on level ground, turn off parking brakes and press brake pedal.",
            "Park on an incline and see if the vehicle rolls."
        ],
        "answer": "Park on level ground, turn off parking brakes, pull hard on each slack adjuster. It shouldn't move more than one inch."
    },
    {
        "question": "60. How can you test the low pressure warning signal?",
        "choices": [
            "While the engine is running, step on and off the brake pedal.",
            "Shut off the engine and see if the air pressure leaks down.",
            "Shut off the engine with enough air pressure, turn on the electrical power and step on and off the brake pedal until the low air pressure warning signal comes on."
        ],
        "answer": "Shut off the engine with enough air pressure, turn on the electrical power and step on and off the brake pedal until the low air pressure warning signal comes on."
    },
    {
        "question": "61. What are the maximum leakage rates?",
        "choices": [
            "Less than 4 psi in one minute for single vehicles and less than 8 psi in one minute for combination vehicles.",
            "Less than 2 psi in one minute for single vehicles and less than 3 psi in one minute for combination vehicles.",
            "Less than 6 psi for all vehicles."
        ],
        "answer": "Less than 2 psi in one minute for single vehicles and less than 3 psi in one minute for combination vehicles."
    },
    {
        "question": "62. When is it OK to leave your truck unattended without applying parking brakes or chocking the wheels?",
        "choices": [
            "If you will only be away from the truck for a few minutes.",
            "Never.",
            "If you are conducting your pre-trip inspection."
        ],
        "answer": "Never."
    },
    {
        "question": "63. If you are away from your vehicle for only a short time you don't need to use the parking brake.",
        "choices": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "64. If you do not have automatic tank drains, how often should you drain the oil and water from the bottom of compressed air storage tanks?",
        "choices": [
            "After every four hours of service.",
            "At the end of each day of driving.",
            "Once a week."
        ],
        "answer": "At the end of each day of driving."
    },
    {
        "question": "65. The use of brakes on a long steep downgrade is only a supplement to the braking effect of the engine.",
        "choices": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "66. What factors can cause brakes to fade or fail?",
        "choices": [
            "Not pressing the brake pedal hard enough.",
            "Over heating, low air pressure, and not relying on the engine braking effect.",
            "Not taking your foot off the accelerator."
        ],
        "answer": "Over heating, low air pressure, and not relying on the engine braking effect."
    },
    {
        "question": "67. Why should you be in the proper gear before starting down a hill?",
        "choices": [
            "So you only have to apply the brake just hard enough to feel a definite slowdown.",
            "So you can coast downhill.",
            "So you can go through the gears on the way down."
        ],
        "answer": "So you only have to apply the brake just hard enough to feel a definite slowdown."
    },
    {
        "question": "68. If oil and water collects in the air tanks what can happen to the brakes?",
        "choices": [
            "The brakes could heat up.",
            "The brakes could fail.",
            "The brakes could lock up."
        ],
        "answer": "The brakes could fail."
    },
    {
        "question": "69. What is the purpose of an alcohol evaporator?",
        "choices": [
            "So you don't have to drain the air tanks as often.",
            "To have a drink available if you get thirsty.",
            "To reduce the risk of ice in the brake valves and other parts in cold weather."
        ],
        "answer": "To reduce the risk of ice in the brake valves and other parts in cold weather."
    },
    {
        "question": "70. What is another name for controlled braking?",
        "choices": [
            "Steady braking.",
            "Squeeze braking.",
            "Hard braking."
        ],
        "answer": "Squeeze braking."
    },
    {
        "question": "71. The brake chamber fills with air pushing the rod out which moves the_______ _______, which twists the_____ _______.",
        "choices": [
            "Brake camshaft and tie rod.",
            "Slack adjuster and tie rod.",
            "Slack adjuster and brake camshaft."
        ],
        "answer": "Slack adjuster and brake camshaft."
    },{
        "question": "72. If your vehicle has an alcohol evaporator you should check and fill the alcohol level everyday during cold weather.",
        "choices": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "73. To test the air service brakes you should:",
        "choices": [
            "Stop the vehicle, put it in low gear, depress the service brake, and then gently pull against the brakes.",
            "Brake firmly while slowly moving backwards.",
            "Brake firmly while slowly moving forward."
        ],
        "answer": "Brake firmly while slowly moving forward."
    }
]
